Contact

kquick@metrohealth.org

www.linkedin.com/in/kevin-quick-rn-bsn-cen-2158023b (LinkedIn) www.metrohealth.org/lifeflight (Company)

Top Skills

Critical Care Nursing

Hospitals

Certifications

Certified Emergency Nurse

Kevin Quick RN, BSN, CEN

Flight Nurse Specialist at MetroHealth Medical Center Cleveland/Akron, Ohio Area

Summary

Flight RN at Cleveland Metro Life Flight. I have been a nurse since 2000. I enjoy working on a team with critical problems to solve. Quality facilitator for Metro Life Flight. Amateur photographer with a few published shots. Very much an amateur golfer. Husband since 1997, and father of 4 great kiddos. Christian, headed for the kingdom.

Experience

MetroHealth Medical Center 15 years 10 months

Flight Nurse Specialist November 2010 - Present (9 years 9 months)

- Providing care for acutely ill patient for inter-facility and scene response via air & ground to a Diverse patient age range dealing with Trauma, Cardiology, Medical, Pediatrics, Obstetrics, and Neonatal emergencies
- Interventions and medical management for acutely ill patients
- Procedures including intubations, Chest Tubes, Pericardiocentesis, Cricothyroidotomy, U/S Fast exams
- Team approach care with one other provider as a RN/RN, RN/MD, RN/NP or RN/2 Medic configuration
- Providing CE for EMS and RN's in public lecture format
- Multiple competency, simulation lab, surgical lab, cadaver lab, and skills lab to maintain competency
- Chair of Multi-Disciplinary Quality committee
- Prepare and be interviewed for MLF's accreditation process for CAMTS
- Fixed wing trips across county and over seas

RN-Emergency Dept
October 2004 - Present (15 years 10 months)
Emergency Dept.

- Level I Trauma Center (75 Bed ED/CDU)
- Student Nurse Preceptor for Case Western Reserve University

- Charge RN
- Preceptor for new staff
- --Diverse age range of patients with diverse medical and surgical needs

RN-SICU/Rapid Response Team

May 2008 - November 2010 (2 years 7 months)

5C SICU (Trauma)

Rapid Response Team duties and responsibilities:

- •Assume care of acute patients outside of critical care units
- ·Assess, plan, and implement care of acute patients
- Assist and suggest strategies to improve patient outcomes with primary service
- Determine placement needs of patients
- •Teach floor nurses and families regarding care of acute symptoms
- •Circulate throughout hospital discussing patients' acuity with charge nurses/ Senior MD's

SICU duties and responsibilities:

- •Charge RN in Trauma SICU/Level I Trauma Center
- Code Blue Team (inpatient)
- Interview new staff
- Train new staff
- Attended one-week hospital disaster training (FEMA) in Alabama (8/08)
- •Pick up shifts in Emergency Department PRN
- •Participate weekly in Multi-Disciplinary trauma rounds
- Care for acutely ill patients in the SICU setting

Assistant Nurse Manager-Emergency Dept

March 2006 - May 2008 (2 years 3 months)

Emergency Dept

•Work with management team to run 75 bed ED/CDU in Level I Trauma

Center

- •Interview, hire, and dismiss staff in ED
- Staff schedule/daily adjustments to scheduling
- •Staff disciplinary actions/work with HR on action plans for staff
- •Write action plans for ED Department improvements
- Write and deliver staff performance evaluations
- Participate in Multi-Disciplinary Medical Operations meetings
- •Review timecards and payroll
- Lead RN and Medic staff meetings
- •Mentor and assist primary preceptors with struggling newly hired employees
- Monitor OT/Benefit time/Hospital Convenience time

- Monitor and track FMLA/Leaves of absence
- •Give orientation lecture to new ED MD residents annually
- •Cover department as staff RN and charge RN during staffing shortage
- •Completed Non-Violent Crisis Intervention (NVCI) Train-the-Trainer (2/2008)

Lorain County Community College Clinical Instructor January 2006 - December 2010 (5 years)

Critical Care ICU (EMH, Fairview)

- •Instructor of up to nine nursing students per semester at Fairview Hosp ICU & EMH ICU
- •Final-year Acute Care setting clinical (ICU Rotation)
- •Evaluate student performance in the clinical setting

EMH Regional Medical Center RN--Emergency Dept. (Patient Care Coordinator) April 2001 - October 2004 (3 years 7 months)

- Emergency Dept
- •Regularly-scheduled Charge Nurse
- Calculation of staff bonuses and payroll
- •Intervention during high-stress, high-culpability situations
- •Member of Policy & Procedures committee
- •Regular member of Code Team
- •Completed Non-violent Crisis Intervention (NVCI) Train-the-Trainer (2/2004)
- •Instructor within hospital for NVCI, training new employees on unit
- --Patient care for a diverse age populaton with multiple healthcare needs

Education

University of Cincinnati
BSN, Bachelor of Science in Nursing · (1996 - 2000)

Baptist Bible College and Seminary Youth Ministry, Youth Ministry (1994 - 1995)